China has achieved a remarkable milestone in artificial intelligence.
Huawei's Ascend chip now controls 50 to 60 percent of China's domestic AI accelerator market, with projected revenues of $12 billion.
At the same time, Tencent released Hi3, a massive 295 billion parameter model, completely for free.
Let's explore how China is building a fully independent AI stack from silicon to software.
The chip war between Huawei and Nvidia is reaching a critical point.
Huawei's Ascend 910C and upcoming 950 series are directly competing with Nvidia's offerings in the Chinese market.
While Nvidia once dominated, Huawei has captured the majority share through aggressive development and government support.
Chinese companies are increasingly choosing domestic chips over imported ones, driven by both policy and performance improvements.
Beyond hardware, China is vertically integrating the entire AI stack.
Tencent's Hi3 model, with its mixture of experts architecture, demonstrates that Chinese AI models can compete with the best in the world.
By making it free, Tencent is accelerating adoption and building an ecosystem around their technology.
This combination of domestic chips running domestic models creates a self-sufficient AI infrastructure that doesn't depend on foreign technology.
China's chip and model dominance has significant geopolitical implications.
With full control over both hardware and software, China can continue AI development regardless of export controls or trade restrictions.
This independent AI stack positions China as a major force in the global AI landscape, reshaping the balance of technological power.