Open source voice AI just hit a major milestone.
Three groundbreaking tools have been released this month that together make the entire voice AI stack completely open source.
Let's dive into what this means.
First up is Jeopard 1.0, a 600 million parameter streaming text-to-speech model released under Apache 2.0.
What makes Jeopard special is that it speaks as text arrives.
No more waiting for the full sentence.
It's built for real-time dialogue with incredibly low latency.
This makes it perfect for voice assistants, live captioning, and interactive applications where natural conversation flow matters.
And it's completely free and open source.
The team behind Voice Arena launched VoiceArena.com, a public leaderboard that compares speech-to-text and text-to-speech models head-to-head.
This is huge for developers trying to pick the right model for their use case.
You can see word error rates, latency, and naturalness scores across dozens of models.
It brings transparency and competition to the voice AI space.
Longcat Avatar is an open source tool that turns a single photo and an audio file into a talking video.
It generates realistic lip sync and head movements. The implications are massive.
Content creators, educators, and businesses can now generate talking head videos without expensive studio equipment or proprietary software.
Jeopard for voice generation, Voice Arena for model comparison, and Longcat Avatar for video creation.
The full voice AI stack is now open, accessible, and ready for you to build with.
The tipping point is here.